



 

   //Questions array

   let questions = [

    {

         number:1,

         question: "___ are seen as building blocks to the sentence ?",

         answer : "Phrases and clauses",

         options : [

                          "Grammar",

                          "Sentence fragments",

                          "Phrases and clauses",

                          "Subject and predicate"

                        ]

    

    },

    {

         number:2,

         question: " The main unit of structure in English grammar is__",

         answer : "Clause",

         options : [

                          "Phrase",

                          "Clause",

                          "Sentence",

                          "Sounds"  

                          ]

    

    },

   {

         number:3,

         question: " __ is a group of words which make incomplete sense",

         answer : "Phrase",

         options : [ 

                          "Phrase",

                          "Clause",

                          "Sentence fragments",

                          "Syllabic formation"

                          ]

    

    },

    {

         number:4,

         question: "When a noun phrases referring to the same thing or person as a subject it serves as the___",

         answer : "Complement",

         options : [

                          "Subject",

                          "Appositive",

                          "Complement",

                          "Object"

                          ]

    }, 

    {

         number:5,

         question: "__ has strict rules of order",

         answer : "Verb phrase",

         options : [ 

                          "Verb phrase",

                          "Prepositional phrase",

                          "Adjectival phrase",

                          "Adverbial phrase"

                       ]

    },

    {

         number:6,

         question: "Phrases are classified according to __",

         answer : "Class of word",

         options : [

                          "Syntactic categories",

                          "Class of word",

                          "Type of phrase",

                          "Grammatical function"

                       ]

    },

    {

         number:7,

         question: "The man at the gate is my father, the underlined group of words is a ___",

         answer : "Noun phrase",

         options : [

                          "Noun phrase",

                          "Adjectival phrase",

                          "Prepositional phrase",

                          "Adverbial phrase"

                       ]

    },

     {

         number:8,

         question: "The book on religious studies is missing, the underlined group of words is a___",

         answer : "Adjectival phrase",

         options : [

                         "Noun phrase",

                         "Adjectival phrase",

                         "Prepositional phrase",

                         "Verb phrase"

                       ]

    },

    {

         number:9,

         question: "The balloon rose off the ground , the underlined group of words is a ___",

         answer : "Prepositional phrase",

         options : [

                         "Noun phrase",

                         "Adjectival phrase",

                         "Prepositional phrase",

                         "Adverbial phrase"

                       ]

    },

    {

         number:10,

         question: "The man kicked the bucket because of illness, the underlined group of words is a___",

         answer : "Adverbial phrase",

         options : [

                         "Noun phrase",

                         "Adjectival phrase",

                         "Prepositional phrase",

                         "Adverbial phrase"

                       ]

    },

    {

         number:11,

         question: "a prepositional phrase modifies a noun or pronoun it acts as ___",

         answer : "Adjective",

         options : [

                         "Adjunct",

                         "Post modifier",

                         "Adverbial",

                         "Adjective"

                       ]

    },

    {

         number:12,

         question: "Which of these is not part of the structure of a phrase",

         answer : "Determiner",

         options : [

                         "Modifier",

                         "Determiner",

                         "Quantifier",

                         "Head"

                       ]

    },

    {

         number:13,

         question: "The most important item in a phrase is ___",

         answer : "Head",

         options : [

                         "Modifier",

                         "Determiner",

                         "Quantifier",

                         "Head"

                       ]

    },

    {

         number:14,

         question: "A clause expresses an action or a ___",

         answer : "State of being",

         options : [

                         "State of being",

                         "Relationship",

                         "Fragment",

                         "Notion"

                       ]

    },

    {

         number:15,

         question: "A group of words with a subject and predicate which cannot stand on its own is called",

         answer : "Subordinate clause",

         options : [

                         "Noun phrase",

                         "Subordinate clause",

                         "Sentence fragment",

                         "Appositive"

                       ]

    },

    {

         number:16,

         question: "The functions of prepositional phrase does not include",

         answer : "Adjective",

         options : [

                         "Post modifier",

                         "Adjective",

                         "Adjunct",

                         "Conjunct"

                       ]

    },

    {

         number:17,

         question: "Noun clauses are introduced by",

         answer : "Subordinators",

         options : [

                         "Modifiers",

                         "Determiner",

                         "Quantifier",

                         "Subordinators"

                       ]

    },

    {

         number:18,

         question: "The subject complement follows a __",

         answer : "Copular verb",

         options : [

                         "Copular verb",

                         "Transitive verb",

                         "Finite verb",

                         "Verb phrase"

                       ]

    },

    {

         number:19,

         question: "If a noun supports another word, phrase or clause by describing it, that noun is in ___",

         answer : "Appositive",

         options : [

                         "Complement",

                         "Adjunct",

                         "Appositive",

                         "Congruence"

                       ]

    },

    {

         number:20,

         question: "Another name for adjectival clause is __",

         answer : "Relative clause",

         options : [

                         "Subordinate clause",

                         "Relative clause",

                         "post modifier",

                         "Quantifier"

                       ]

    },

    {

         number:21,

         question: "What he said was recorded on tape, the underlined group of words is",

         answer : "Noun clause",

         options : [

                         "Noun clause",

                         "Adverbial clause",

                         "Prepositional clause",

                         "adjectival clause"

                       ]

    },

    {

         number:22,

         question: "The house I told you about has been demolished, the underlined group of words is",

         answer : "adjectival clause",

         options : [

                         "Noun clause",

                         "Adverbial clause",

                         "Prepositional clause",

                         "adjectival clause"

                       ]

    },

    {

         number:23,

         question: "I always like to study where there is no noise. , The underlined group of words is",

         answer : "Adverbial clause",

         options : [

                         "Noun clause",

                         "Adverbial clause",

                         "Prepositional clause",

                         "adjectival clause"

                       ]

    },

    {

         number:24,

         question: "Which one is not a type of subordinate clause",

         answer : "Prepositional clause",

         options : [

                         "Noun clause",

                         "Adverbial clause",

                         "Prepositional clause",

                         "adjectival clause"

                       ]

    }

     ];    